[
  {
    ID: "1",
    Question: "You are working on a project as an Agile Project Manager. The executive manager who will own the product you are delivering would like to focus primarily on set processes and tools to manage to project. What will you recommend to them instead?",
    A: "To focus on the definition of success as defined by the project manager.",
    B: "Focus primarily on the individuals and interactions involved.",
    C: "Focus primarily on the scope of the project.",
    D: "Focus primarily on the schedule of the project.",
    Answer: "Focus primarily on the individuals and interactions involved.",
    Reason: "The Agile manifesto recommends focusing on Individuals and Interactions over processes and tools. Projects are run by people, products are developed by people for people to use and our interactions either make or break a project."
  },
  {
    ID: "2",
    Question: "The executive management in your organization has assembled a new team, and dictated that they will use Agile for their product development. As the project progresses, there is confusion about the product scope and the definition of what done looks like. As an Agile Project Manager, what will you recommend to the executive team?",
    A: "Select a person from each part of the organization to assist, to ensure diversity.",
    B: "Have the functional manager select their friends or favorite team member.",
    C: "Encourage a self-organizing team to form, including the people who asked for the requirements and outcomes in the first place.",
    D: "Hire external consultants to run the project and create the product.",
    Answer: "Encourage a self-organizing team to form, including the people who asked for the requirements and outcomes in the first place.",
    Reason: "Agile encourages self-organizing teams composed of the people who created the requirements and had the desired outcome in the first place. This gives a higher level of ownership and product expertise, that often cannot be bought."
  },
  {
    ID: "3",
    Question: "You are running an Agile project and meet with the team for the next sprint planning meeting. What will you do next?",
    A: "Negotiate the scope and costs of the project with the project sponsor.",
    B: "Walk through three questions with the team--what did I do yesterday? What will I do today? Is anything blocking me?",
    C: "The dev team demonstrates the working feature to the product owner, who marks it complete.",
    D: "The product owner shares the updated backlog, and the team discusses it to ensure a shared understanding.",
    Answer: "The product owner shares the updated backlog, and the team discusses it to ensure a shared understanding.",
    Reason: "The product owner should share the updated backlog items and ensure the entire team has a good understanding of how to move forward."
  },
  {
    ID: "4",
    Question: "You are a project manager working on an Agile project and want your team to maximize the value they bring to the customer. What can you eliminate in order to maximize project value?",
    A: "Daily stand-ups.",
    B: "Unnecessary features.",
    C: "Sprint reviews.",
    D: "Testing.",
    Answer: "Unnecessary features.",
    Reason: "In addition to eliminating the introduction of unnecessary features, value can be maximized by eliminating partially done work, delays, extra processes and features, task switching, waiting, moving information or a deliverable, defects or rework, and handoffs."
  },
  {
    ID: "5",
    Question: "You are working on a project and the team have recently moved to an Agile way of work. One of the team members is confused about Scrum and what typically happens after the sprint review. What will you tell them happens next?",
    A: "Hold a sprint retrospective with the team.",
    B: "Perform product backlog refinement with the product owner.",
    C: "Perform story card elaboration with the three amigos (Business, Development, Testing).",
    D: "Hold a Daily Scrum.",
    Answer: "Hold a sprint retrospective with the team.",
    Reason: "A sprint retrospective is held with the Whole Team, after a sprint review, but before the sprint planning meeting. We use it to gather lessons learned and look for opportunities for improvement, and everyone has a voice for feedback and to implement improvements before the next sprint."
  },
  {
    ID: "6",
    Question: "You are working in an Agile team and preparing the Agile team charter. You work with the Agile team to ensure the team charter answers these four questions: Why are we doing the project? Who benefits and how?",
    A: "When will the project end? What do we do with the product?",
    B: "What does done mean for the project? How are we going to work together?",
    C: "How much risk is on the project? What is the project scope?",
    D: "How many defects are allowed in the product? How many testers are there?",
    Answer: "What does done mean for the project? How are we going to work together?",
    Reason: "An Agile team charter typically covers why we are doing the project, who benefits and how, what does done look like, and how are we going to work together. (See Agile Practice Guide, Ch 5, p.49)"
  },
  {
    ID: "7",
    Question: "You are working with a new Agile project manager and explain that Agile favors value-based measurements instead of predictive measurements on a project. What is an example of value-based measurements?",
    A: "Earned value management and the schedule performance index.",
    B: "Variance Analysis and the Estimate to Complete.",
    C: "Feature burndown chart (features delivered) and customer satisfaction.",
    D: "Variance at Completion and the cost performance index.",
    Answer: "Feature burndown chart (features delivered) and customer satisfaction.",
    Reason: "Agile works with value delivered as its primary measurement. All the other options are predictive measurements from a traditional project management methodology."
  },
  {
    ID: "8",
    Question: "Agile Unified Process (AUP) is an Auxiliary Agile method that focuses on performing more iterative cycles across seven key disciplines, and incorporating the associated feedback before formal delivery. Which is NOT one of the seven key disciplines within a release?",
    A: "Discipline of the high level model.",
    B: "Discipline in managing stakeholders' expectations.",
    C: "Discipline in testing.",
    D: "Discipline in configuration management.",
    Answer: "Discipline in managing stakeholders' expectations.",
    Reason: "Agile focuses on transparency to ensure the customer needs are met, not in specifically managing customer expectations."
  },
  {
    ID: "9",
    Question: "You are leading a coaching session with your project team on the additional Agile and Lean frameworks that have contributed to the Agile way of work. What frameworks will you share with the team?",
    A: "Project Management Plan, Project Charter.",
    B: "Scaled Agile Framework, Large Scale Scrum.",
    C: "Working Group Meetings, Project Post Mortems.",
    D: "Flow Charting, Affinity Diagrams.",
    Answer: "Scaled Agile Framework, Large Scale Scrum.",
    Reason: "Agile and Lean frameworks include Scaled Agile Framework, Large Scale Scrum, Scrum of Scrums, Dynamic Systems Development Method, along with the more common Kanban, Extreme Programming and Scrum."
  },
  {
    ID: "10",
    Question: "Introduced by Alexander Cockburn in his book Crystal Clear and created at IBM in 1991, Crystal is an Agile framework focusing on individuals and their interactions, as opposed to processes and tools (the first Agile principle). It is not a set process, but a guideline for team collaboration and communication. Which of the following is NOT one of its core beliefs?",
    A: "Technologies change techniques.",
    B: "People change functions.",
    C: "Cultures change norms.",
    D: "Distances change communication.",
    Answer: "People change functions.",
    Reason: "Crystal Clear describes the three core beliefs as Technologies changing techniques, cultures changing norms, and distances changing communication - all reasons behind the core practices of Agile such as stand-ups, collaborative user story, creation, retrospectives and the whole team approach."
  },
  {
    ID: "11",
    Question: "You are working on a project in the role of Scrum Master, and have set a meeting with the team and the product owner to refine the product abcklog. What should the team do in this meeting?",
    A: "Estimate and refine the work items.",
    B: "Prioritize the work items.",
    C: "Add features to the project backlog.",
    D: "Identify fixes.",
    Answer: "Estimate and refine the work items.",
    Reason: "The product owner adjusts the priority of product backlog items. The team is responsible for estimating and refining work items. Each time the team refines their estimates with a higher level of detail."
  },
  {
    ID: "12",
    Question: "You are working with a team who would like to become Agile. The function manager asks you what the difference between Kanban and Scrum is. What will you tell them?",
    A: "Kanban teams plan with work in sprints or iterations.",
    B: "There are no WIP limits in Kanban.",
    C: "Kanban teams work on a project as a whole.",
    D: "Kanban teams employ a pull system.",
    Answer: "Kanban teams employ a pull system.",
    Reason: "The main difference between Scrum and Kanban is that Kanban teams employ a pull system. This means when an item of work is completed, it triggers someone to pull the next item in the queue onto the board to work on. Kanban teams work off a Kanban board that displays each task, and have a limit to how much work in progress (WIP) can be in place."
  },
  {
    ID: "13",
    Question: "You are working on a new project with an Agile product development team, who have self-formed and chosen a Scrum Master called Jeremy. Jeremy immediately sets a meeting with the team to explain and flesh out their Team Charter. What has made Jeremy a good choice for Scrum Master?",
    A: "He likes to work within set processes.",
    B: "He has been with the company for more than five years.",
    C: "He knows servant leadership and engages the team in decisions.",
    D: "He sticks to the plan and does not change.",
    Answer: "He knows servant leadership and engages the team in decisions.",
    Reason: "Jeremy shows the traits of servant leadership by engaging the team in team decisions, starting with the Team Charter and ground rules so everyone knows where they stand. By communicating the reasons for his decisions, he is a suitable Scrum Master and will be less focused on command and control."
  },
  {
    ID: "14",
    Question: "You are managing a project as an Agile project manager and a business representative for the product you are delivering asks you how many defects were found in the latest round of testing. You don't know the answer. What should you do?",
    A: "Guess the number then change the subject.",
    B: "Tell the business partner you will send an e-mail to him with the information.",
    C: "Take him into the team area, where the information radiator with project information is displayed.",
    D: "Ask the business partner to call the Scrum Master to get a correct answer.",
    Answer: "Take him into the team area, where the information radiator with project information is displayed.",
    Reason: "A core component of Agile is Visual Management and transparency. Part of this are the various parts of the project information radiator (often physical, but can be tech-driven). This includes things such as the team velocity, Kanban board, the product backlog, the burndown chart, the latest test results and issues, and results of retrospectives."
  },
  {
    ID: "15",
    Question: "You are working in a company that is moving from a Waterfall methodology to Agile. You mention to the business unit manager that the team will be better prepared to respond to change and meet the customer needs. Why is this?",
    A: "The Agile team works directly with a business owner or representative to constantly prioritize delivered value.",
    B: "The Agile team delivers the product all in one go.",
    C: "The Agile team is for developers only, so development will improve.",
    D: "The business partners review statuses and ask for recommendations.",
    Answer: "The Agile team works directly with a business owner or representative to constantly prioritize delivered value.",
    Reason: "Working with business partners or someone who reperesents the customer almost daily is a key part of Agile. The team hears what the business would like the results to be, and meeting face-to-face is better than reading requirements, documents, e-mails, or even a conference call."
  },
  {
    ID: "16",
    Question: "For Agile life-cycles, two kinds of planning occur, release planning and iteration planning. In release planning, business representatives establish and prioritize the user stories for the release, in collaboration with the team, refining larger user stories into a collection of smaller stories. What is the INCORRECT description below regarding iteration planning and backlog preparation?",
    A: "The backlog is the ordered list of all the work, present in story form, for a team.",
    B: "The project coach encourages the team to work alone, so no one bothers them.",
    C: "The facilitator encourages the team to work in triads of a developer, tester, and product owner/business analyst.",
    D: "The triad discus, write, and then place enough stories into an iteration, and enough features for a first release.",
    Answer: "The project coach encourages the team to work alone, so no one bothers them.",
    Reason: "Answers A, C, and D are correct in describing Backlog Preparation for Iteration Planning."
  },
  {
    ID: "17",
    Question: "Behaviour-driven development (BDD) allows a developer to focus on testing the code based on the expected behaviour of the software and is a method of writing user stories. What is the correct description regarding BDD acceptance-based criteria?",
    A: "Make, Buy, Do.",
    B: "Tell, Show, Repeat.",
    C: "Find, Create, Perform.",
    D: "Given, When, Then.",
    Answer: "Given, When, Then.",
    Reason: "Given, When, Then is the way BDD is used, particularly when outlining user Story Cards for your iteration. It highlights Given a certain situation, When something happens, Then we want this to happen."
  },
  {
    ID: "18",
    Question: "Every project has characteristics around requirements, delivery, change and goals. Understanding the different types of life cycle, you can choose the right one for the circumstatnces of your project. What is the correct description for a Waterfall approach?",
    A: "Predictive - Fix requirements, performed once for the entire project, in a single delivery.",
    B: "Predictive - Fixed requirements, performed multiple times for the entire project, in multiple deliveries.",
    C: "Predictive - Variable requirements, performed once for the entire project in a single delivery.",
    D: "Predictive - Variable requirements, performed multiple times for the entire project, in multiple deliveries.",
    Answer: "Predictive - Fix requirements, performed once for the entire project, in a single delivery.",
    Reason: "A Predictive or Waterfall project management lifecycle focuses on fixed requirements performed once for the project for a single delivery."
  },
  {
    ID: "19",
    Question: "Every project has characteristics around requirements, delivery, change and goals. Understand the different types of life cycles will allow you to choose the right one for the circumstances of your project. What is the correct description for an Iterative project approach?",
    A: "Dynamic requirements, repeated until correct, in multiple deliveries.",
    B: "Dynamic requirements, repeated until correct, in a single delivery.",
    C: "Fixed requirements, repeated until incorrect, in a single delivery.",
    D: "Fixed requirements, performed once for a given increment, in a single delivery.",
    Answer: "Dynamic requirements, repeated until correct, in a single delivery.",
    Reason: "Iterative methods have dynamic requirements, repeated with feedback until they are correct, but delivered only once."
  },
  {
    ID: "20",
    Question: "You are walking through the next feature with the product owner in an Agile team. He is new to Agile, and unsure of what Kanban really is. He lists a few things for you to check. Which of the following is NOT one of the core properties of Kanban?",
    A: "Visualize the workflow and limit work in progress.",
    B: "Manage Flow and Enable Pull.",
    C: "Implement feedback loops and improve collaboratively.",
    D: "Follow procedures and don't deviate from the plan.",
    Answer: "Follow procedures and don't deviate from the plan.",
    Reason: "Kanban is a method borrowed from the Toyota Production System, or Lean. It focuses on limiting the work in progress so work is focused, ensuring feedback loops are in place, and making the work visible so blockages are clear."
  },
  {
    ID: "21",
    Question: "A Team Charter is also a social contract. Which of the below is NOT usually a part of an Agile Team Charter?",
    A: "Team values, such as sustainable pace and core hours.",
    B: "Working agreements, such as what ready means so the team can take in work, and what done means so the team can judge completeness consistently.",
    C: "Ground rules, such as one person talking in a meeting.",
    D: "Schedule performance index and cost performance indext for the project.",
    Answer: "Schedule performance index and cost performance indext for the project.",
    Reason: "The Agile Team Charter focuses on the vision (the Why) and the team way of work. SPI and CPI are earned value management metriccs from a predictive project methodology, and not part of an Agile Team Charter."
  },
  {
    ID: "22",
    Question: "You are working with a team that is new to Agile and are using Scrum to manage the project. The business representative is confused about the difference between a sprint review and a sprint retrospective. What will you tell them?",
    A: "Sprint review demonstrate the work completed in the sprint. Sprint retrospectives look at all work completed in the project.",
    B: "Sprint reviews discuss what is worked on in the sprint. Sprint retrospectives are done at the end of the project for a lessons learned opportunity.",
    C: "Sprint reviews review the lessons learned. Sprint retrospectives look at the history of the product retrospectively.",
    D: "Sprint reviews are for product demonstrations. Sprint retrospectives are for lessons learned.",
    Answer: "Sprint reviews are for product demonstrations. Sprint retrospectives are for lessons learned.",
    Reason: "Sprint reviews are for product demonstrations. Sprint retrospectives are for lessons learned, where we ask What went well, what didn't go well, what did I learn?"
  },
  {
    ID: "23",
    Question: "You are working on an Agile project as a team member, and begin gathering the product requirements. What is the overall first questions that you should ask and use as a guide for your work?",
    A: "How long will the project last?",
    B: "What is the business value?",
    C: "How much is the budget?",
    D: "How many team members will participate?",
    Answer: "What is the business value?",
    Reason: "Agile projects centre around delivering business value, and working closely with the customers and business representatives to ensure that the value is always correct. Business risk and the impact of not understaing the project must also be considered."
  },
  {
    ID: "24",
    Question: "The Agile team for which you are the project manager has determined several key features to deliver to the customer. How should these tasks be tackled by the team?",
    A: "The features should be priotized, tested, and delivered incrementally.",
    B: "The features should be delivered quickly, whether or not they are complete, to gather feedback.",
    C: "The features should be delivered according to the project plan.",
    D: "All features should be delivered at the end of the project.",
    Answer: "The features should be priotized, tested, and delivered incrementally.",
    Reason: "Agile is a combination of Incremental delivery and Iterative development. That means business value is continuously and iteratively improved and prioritized, while also being delivered in increments that the customer can see, feel, and touch. The features should be complete tested, and quality is everyone's responsibility."
  },
  {
    ID: "25",
    Question: "You are working on an Agile project and the project team have just finished an iteration. All tasks for the iteration have been completed, and you are ready to move to the next iteration, but are not sure what the team should work on. What will you do next?",
    A: "Follow the project plan developed early in the project.",
    B: "Follow the PMO, who has already determined how the project should progress.",
    C: "Ask the product owner, who continuously prioritizes the backlog.",
    D: "Ask the project coach or team leader to determine the next iteration.",
    Answer: "Ask the product owner, who continuously prioritizes the backlog.",
    Reason: "The product owner represents the customer, who you are delivering business value to. The team works through the list of items that have identifiable value and have been prioritized by the customer."
  },
  {
    ID: "26",
    Question: "While meeting with the customers or business owners, they introduce several pieces of new functionality into the product backlog list. The deadline for the product cannot be changed. What will you do next?",
    A: "Tell the team to work overtime in order to deliver the project.",
    B: "Stand by your team and tell the customers the project will not be delivered on time.",
    C: "Be sure the customers understand that lower priority features may drop off the project completely.",
    D: "Agree with the customers to have all new items put into a separate category that will be completed if time allows.",
    Answer: "Be sure the customers understand that lower priority features may drop off the project completely.",
    Reason: "An Agile project can accept changes even late in development. But while the competing constraints of cost, quality and schedule are often fixed, in Agile the scope can vary. This means some features may need to drop off, as others become prioritized. A maintainable pace of work is required too - the project managers must not overwork the project team to increase the pace of the project work."
  },
  {
    ID: "27",
    Question: "Every project has characteristics around requirements, delivery, change and goals. Understanding the different types of life cycle will allow you to choose the right one for the circumstances of your project. What is the correct description for an Incremental project management approach?",
    A: "Fixed requirements, activities performed once, in multiple deliveries.",
    B: "Dynamic requirements, activities repeated until correct, in one large delivery.",
    C: "Dynamic requirements, performed once for a given increment, in frequent smaller deliveries.",
    D: "Fixed requirements, performed once for a given increment, in frequent smaller deliveries.",
    Answer: "Dynamic requirements, performed once for a given increment, in frequent smaller deliveries.",
    Reason: "Incremental project management approach includes dynamic requirements, performed once for a given increment, with frequent smaller deliveries."
  },
  {
    ID: "28",
    Question: "There are certain core practices that are common amongst all the various Agile frameworks, and used within any team that calls themselves Agile. Which of the below is NOT a core Agile practice?",
    A: "Team Iteration Planning",
    B: "Collaborative User Story Creation between the business, customer, developers and testers.",
    C: "Demonstrations and Reviews of the features developed.",
    D: "Autocratic Leadership, to ensure the work gets done.",
    Answer: "Autocratic Leadership, to ensure the work gets done.",
    Reason: "The preferred style of leadership in an Agile team is Servant Leadership. Autocratic leadership typically is a one person affair, while servant leadership builds psychological safety for the whole team to engage and contribue. All other items listed are Agile core practices."
  },
  {
    ID: "29",
    Question: "Poor specifications are often a major reason for project failure. In Agile development, user stories are written with the developers, testers, and business representatives, with frequent reviews to ensure they are right. Which of the following is NOT correct regarding Collaborative User Story Creation?",
    A: "A user story addresses both function and non-function requirements.",
    B: "The project sponsor must sign off on all user stories in advance.",
    C: "A user story includes acceptance criteria for the feature to be developed.",
    D: "Characteristics for acceptance criteria must be: Estimatable, Small, and Testable.",
    Answer: "The project sponsor must sign off on all user stories in advance.",
    Reason: "While it is common for the developers, testers, and business representatives to agree on the story card criteria, it is not signed off by the project sponsor directly. The product owner, representing the business and/or the customer, grooms the feature backlog work so they always know that business value is being delivered."
  },
  {
    ID: "30",
    Question: "In Continuous Integration: configuration management, compilation, software build, deployment, and testing are wrapped into a single, automated, repeatable process. Defects in code are:",
    A: "not an issue during continuous integration, making it an ideal Agile method.",
    B: "detected more quickly because they constantly integrate their work, build and test.",
    C: "integrated into their work during this phase as part of Test Driven Development.",
    D: "collected and fixed in an iteration at the end of the project, to avoid delay.",
    Answer: "detected more quickly because they constantly integrate their work, build and test.",
    Reason: "Continuous Integration merges code to a test environment using an automated process, including automated regression tests to ensure nothing is broken. This allows the team to find and fix defects in the code more quickly. Test Driven Development writes a test first (which fails at first), then the code to ensure the test passes."
  },
  {
    ID: "31",
    Question: "Agile has certain core practices that are used within any team working in an Agile way. Which of the following is NOT a core practice of Agile?",
    A: "The whole team approach, where any person needed is brought into the project team.",
    B: "Early and frequent feedback, to ensure a common understanding of the product.",
    C: "Daily stand-ups, to report on progress and raise blockers.",
    D: "Reporting to executives, to ensure they are happy with your project.",
    Answer: "Reporting to executives, to ensure they are happy with your project.",
    Reason: "While reporting to executives has its place when running a project, in Agile it would rather be done by including them in other Agile core practices, such as demonstrations or reviews of the product, showing the product burndown chart in the team area, and the backlog of work. All other items are Agile core practices."
  },
  {
    ID: "32",
    Question: "You are working on a project as an Agile project manager. You look at the product backlog and ensure several features, or minimum viable products (MVPs) can be scheduled for delivery throughout the duration of the project. Why is this a good idea?",
    A: "To show executives that progress is being made by the development team.",
    B: "To keep the project duration short.",
    C: "To enable users to test the product for quality, and give feedback.",
    D: "To enable the business to get value quickly, as features are delivered.",
    Answer: "To enable the business to get value quickly, as features are delivered.",
    Reason: "Minimum Viable Products are usable features in their own right that are delivered incrementally. This allows for business value to be gained more quickly, while gathering feedback on the use of these features."
  },
  {
    ID: "33",
    Question: "You are working on a complex software project but see that the team uses a whiteboard, and writes tasks on cards or sticky notes. The business representative seems put off by the use of these low-tech tools on such a high profile technology project. What will you tell them?",
    A: "The team are using low-tech tools so low-tech people can understand them.",
    B: "A whiteboard is actually a complex thing, they just don't know it yet.",
    C: "The team is using the principle of visual management, and by using a physical board it is transparent to anyone who needs the information.",
    D: "The team will drop everything and develop a new software-based Kanban board to avoid embarrassment.",
    Answer: "The team is using the principle of visual management, and by using a physical board it is transparent to anyone who needs the information.",
    Reason: "Visual Management is a Lean principle borrowed into Agile, where we make key pieces of information as accessible as possible. Often found in the team area and often physical, it means anyone can walk through the area and see what they need at a glance. Kanban is an example of a low-tech/high-touch tool."
  },
  {
    ID: "34",
    Question: "Agile teams practice frequent verification and validation during and at the end of each iteration through demonstrations and reviews. Which one of the following is NOT a benefit of this method?",
    A: "It enables the team to catch mistakes and mismatched customer expectations early.",
    B: "It keeps everyone busy and gives them something to do.",
    C: "It is easy to manage since there are multiple feedback loops.",
    D: "It reduces cost overruns as mistakes are found early prior to additional tasks being built upon a faulty foundation.",
    Answer: "It keeps everyone busy and gives them something to do.",
    Reason: "Busy-work does not add value to the project, and is not a benefit of Agile."
  },
  {
    ID: "35",
    Question: "You are on an Agile software implementation project with a very short deadline. How do Agile teams shorten the time between identifying a defect and resolving the defect?",
    A: "Continuous integration.",
    B: "Daily build and smoke tests.",
    C: "Usability testing.",
    D: "Exploratory testing.",
    Answer: "Continuous integration.",
    Reason: "Continuous Integration aims to merge code and have a working build once a day, then executes automated tests quickly to see if anything is broken. This frequent checking ensures less time passes before a problem is identified."
  },
  {
    ID: "36",
    Question: "With all the different methods of testing either a software or product deliverable, when should the team determine the acceptance test criteria for the feature or story card?",
    A: "When the first iteration is complete.",
    B: "During estimation and elaboration of the card, with the product owner, business analysis and development team.",
    C: "Before the product or feature is prioritized.",
    D: "At the end of the project.",
    Answer: "During estimation and elaboration of the card, with the product owner, business analysis and development team.",
    Reason: "Acceptance tests and criteria are designed before the development of a deliverable, and during elaboration, often in a Given, When, Then scenario or an As a, I want, So I can, scenario."
  },
  {
    ID: "37",
    Question: "Every project has characteristics around requirements, delivery, change, and goals. Understanding the different types of life cycle will allow you to choose the right one for the circumstances of your project. Choose the correct description for an Agile approach.",
    A: "Agile - Dynamic requirements, repeated until correct, in frequent small deliveries.",
    B: "Agile - Fixed requirements, repeated until correct, in frequent small deliveries.",
    C: "Agile - Dynamic requirements, repeated until correct, in a single large delivery.",
    D: "Agile - Fixed requirements, performed once for the entire project, in frequent deliveries.",
    Answer: "Agile - Dynamic requirements, repeated until correct, in frequent small deliveries.",
    Reason: "The Agile project management approach includes dynamic requirements, repeated until correct, with frequent smaller deliveries."
  },
  {
    ID: "38",
    Question: "Continuous Integration wraps software build, development, and testing into a single, automated, repeatable process. This merges all changes made to the software and:",
    A: "separates each feature into its own development pool.",
    B: "ensures no code is changed, to avoid complication.",
    C: "integrates all changed components regularly, at least once a day.",
    D: "enables new features for the product backlog.",
    Answer: "integrates all changed components regularly, at least once a day.",
    Reason: "Continuous integration is designed to merge all changes made to the software and test them automatically, discovering any defects or issues on a daily basis."
  },
  {
    ID: "39",
    Question: "Crystal is one of the original frameworks that contributed to Agile. It is designed to scale and realizes that each project may require a slightly tailored set of practices based on size and complexity. Its core values include:",
    A: "People, Interaction, and Community.",
    B: "Finding people, building people, leading people.",
    C: "Building products, buying products, selling products.",
    D: "Profit, Persistence, and Power.",
    Answer: "People, Interaction, and Community.",
    Reason: "Crystal's core values include People, Interaction, and Community - in the same way as Agile is based around iterations over processes and tools - and understanding the impact things have on way of work and getting things done."
  },
  {
    ID: "40",
    Question: "Crystal is designed to scale and realizes that each project may require a slightly tailored set of practices based on size and complexity. What are some of the ways that Crystal scales?",
    A: "Crystal blue, indigo and violet, based on number of features in the backlog.",
    B: "Crystal clear, yellow or red, based on number of people involved.",
    C: "Crystal metal, wood and water, based on the flow of story cards through the Kanban board.",
    D: "Crystal High, Low, and Medium, based on dollars spent on the project.",
    Answer: "Crystal clear, yellow or red, based on number of people involved.",
    Reason: "Crystal clear, yellow, orange and red are based on factors such as people involved (0 to 8, all the way up to 100 or more), money involved and the general comfort level of the project."
  },
  {
    ID: "41",
    Question: "You are working through and Agile project with your team, meeting daily in a daily stand-up. What is NOT one of the reasons Agile teams use daily stand-ups?",
    A: "To micro commit to the team.",
    B: "To uncover and remove blockers.",
    C: "To ensure work flows freely through the team.",
    D: "To report to the executive team.",
    Answer: "To report to the executive team.",
    Reason: "Stand-ups are used to the micro-commit to each other, uncover blockers, and ensure work flows freely through the team. While everyone (including an executive) is welcome to join the stand-ups, they are not specifically for reporting to an executive team."
  },
  {
    ID: "42",
    Question: "You are the project manager on an Agile project that is half way through. The project sponsor is starting to raise concerns that the project will not be completed in the allotted time. What will you do to gather the information necessary to answer the project sponsor?",
    A: "Review the Kanban board and the current WIP.",
    B: "Check the product backlog for remaining features.",
    C: "Review the team velocity, product burndown chart and other key performance indicators.",
    D: "Have a team meeting and log everyone's status.",
    Answer: "Review the team velocity, product burndown chart and other key performance indicators.",
    Reason: "Agile Key Performance Indicators include team velocity (rate of progress) and remaining work. These can be shown visually as well, such as on a burndown chart. Reviewing these KPIs will give you the most reliable answer."
  },
  {
    ID: "43",
    Question: "You are attending the kick-ff meeting with the Agile team and the business owners. The Scrum Master recommends using MoSCow to help prioritize the work with the product/business owners. How does MoSCoW prioritize the product backlog?",
    A: "Using Priority 1, Priority 2, Priority 3, Priority 4.",
    B: "Using Low, Medium, High.",
    C: "Using must have, should have, could have, will not have.",
    D: "Using multiple dots that people can assign to the features they like.",
    Answer: "Using must have, should have, could have, will not have.",
    Reason: "The MoSCoW method of prioritization labels tasks as must have, should have, could have, and will not have (or would like to have). Other prioritization techniques are multi-voting with dots, monopoly money, Kano analysis, and fist of five."
  },
  {
    ID: "44",
    Question: "Agile teams use different methods to manage work in progress (WIP). The business sponsor believes that removing the limits to work in progress will help the team take on more work and get their product delivered faster. What will you tell them?",
    A: "You will remove the limits and push as much work through as possible.",
    B: "You will dictate overtime and no holidays for the team to get things done.",
    C: "WIP Limits ensure the team focuses on one main thing at a time, and avoids the time cost of switching tasks.",
    D: "WIP can be seen on the Kanban board, so it doesn't matter what the limit is.",
    Answer: "WIP Limits ensure the team focuses on one main thing at a time, and avoids the time cost of switching tasks.",
    Reason: "In Agile, work is taken on based on the team velocity or rate of work. The Kanban board shows the WIP and who is working on what. Knowing the velocity allows you to ensure enough work is taken on, but not too much. Research has proven that multitasking or switching tasks actually reduces effectiveness as the team gets up to speed again."
  },
  {
    ID: "45",
    Question: "You are on an Agile team that includes many stakeholders who have not worked with an Agile project in the past. Several stakeholders have some valid concerns about some Agile methods. As a servant leader or project coach, what will you do to make them more comfortable with the process?",
    A: "Educate stakeholders, address their concerns, and keep them engaged.",
    B: "Tell them it has worked in the past, it will work here too.",
    C: "Dictate to the stakeholders that this is how all future projects must be executed.",
    D: "Go back to a Waterfall style project management method.",
    Answer: "Educate stakeholders, address their concerns, and keep them engaged.",
    Reason: "A servant leader includes the team in decisions, and grows the team through education and coaching."
  },
  {
    ID: "46",
    Question: "You are working on an Agile project with stakeholders who are keen to know: Why is it so important to incorprate multiple touchpoints with them before, during, and after iterations?",
    A: "To raise and manage changes, and identify potential risks and issues.",
    B: "To inform the stakeholders of the development team's direction.",
    C: "To ensure business executives hear about the team's value with multiple meetings.",
    D: "To have them invest more time in the project so they are committed.",
    Answer: "To raise and manage changes, and identify potential risks and issues.",
    Reason: "Frequent touch points in Agile are there to ensure the features are reviewed and meet stakeholders' expectations, and risks are addressed. It allows changes to be raised early. Quality is everyone's responsibility on an Agile team."
  },
  {
    ID: "47",
    Question: "Teams use daily stand-ups to micro-commit to each other, uncover and remove blockers, and ensure work flows smoothly through the team. What is NOT true about stand-ups?",
    A: "They are often time-boxed to 15 minutes.",
    B: "The team walks through the Kanban or task board.",
    C: "The team facilitator or anyon in the team can facilitate.",
    D: "Only people in the project team can attend.",
    Answer: "Only people in the project team can attend.",
    Reason: "Agile teams are open and transparent, and encourages stakeholders to pull information or work when needed. Anyone can attend, to learn, watch or contribute. Stand-ups are time-boxed to 15 minutes, the team walks through the Kanban board, and anyone in the team can facilitate."
  },
  {
    ID: "48",
    Question: "Features are completed in an Agile project, usually in the form of multiple user stories. When a feature is complete, the team periodically demonstrates the working product to the customer, business representative and/or the product owner. These demonstrations or reviews:",
    A: "only occur at the end of the project, or when stakeholders are available.",
    B: "often occur at the end of an iteration, or when enough features have been ocmpleted into a set that is coherent.",
    C: "often occur at the start of the project so everyone knows what they have to deliver.",
    D: "often occur when the team wants to, as they are so busy working anyway.",
    Answer: "often occur at the end of an iteration, or when enough features have been ocmpleted into a set that is coherent.",
    Reason: "Agile sprint reviews, or feature demonstrations, occur at the end of an iteration or when enough cards or features have been completed into a set that can be showcased."
  },
  {
    ID: "49",
    Question: "Disciplined Agile (DA) is a process decision framework that blends various Agile techniques. Which of the following principles are NOT a part of DA?",
    A: "People first: Enumerating roles and organization elements at various levels.",
    B: "Learning oriented: Encouraging collaborative improvement.",
    C: "Self promotion: Working to improves your own personal brand.",
    D: "Goal driven: Tailoring processes to achieve specific outcomes.",
    Answer: "Self promotion: Working to improves your own personal brand.",
    Reason: "Agile works transparently for all and with all stakeholders in mind. Self promotion is not a part of the Agile way. Instead, the team serves each other, ensures blockers are removed and information is freely available."
  },
  {
    ID: "50",
    Question: "Disciplined Agile is a process decision framework that blends various Agile techniques. Which of the following principles are from DA?",
    A: "Learning-oriented, Goal-driven and Scalable.",
    B: "Implementing, Iterating and Integrating.",
    C: "Excellence, Guidence and Cadence.",
    D: "Making, Doing, Being.",
    Answer: "Learning-oriented, Goal-driven and Scalable.",
    Reason: "Learning-oriented, goal-driven and scalable are all themes within Agile, and are key principles of the Disciplined Agile Framework."
  },
  {
    ID: "51",
    Question: "You have been assigned to a new project, where the work is behind schedule and the team are not working together well. The team is relatively new, and conflicts are arising. Team members are blaming each other for work not done, and some people are not showing up to work on the project at all. What will you do next?",
    A: "Meet with the functional manager to agree on the team members' time requirements.",
    B: "Meet with your team to set a team charter and define roles & responsibilities.",
    C: "Meet with the project sponsor to gain additional funding for resources who can work together.",
    D: "Escalate the issue to the steering committee as soon as possible as a project risk.",
    Answer: "Meet with your team to set a team charter and define roles & responsibilities.",
    Reason: "The Standard for Project Management asks that we create a collaborative team environment, including team agreements, definitions of roles & responsibilities, formal committees tasked with specific objectives, and standing meetings that regularly review a given topic."
  },
  {
    ID: "52",
    Question: "You have recently completed a project for a new product and have been asked to manage it after its release to keep it relevant in today's marketplace. Half of your existing project team are rolling off to other projects soon, and your project budget is nearly depleted. What will you do next?",
    A: "Create a business case and project charter for your project sponsor to approve.",
    B: "Retain as many of your current project staff to continue work on the project.",
    C: "Raise a change request for your current project to add scope and continue making changes.",
    D: "Secure funding for a stable team, then use current research to form a suite of projects to improve the product.",
    Answer: "Secure funding for a stable team, then use current research to form a suite of projects to improve the product.",
    Reason: "This question is referring to product management. Product management involves the integration of people, data, processes and business systems to develop or maintain a product or service throughout its lifecycle."
  },
  {
    ID: "53",
    Question: "You are delivering a critical change and several key stakeholders in your organization have added seemingly unnecessary steps for you to take, with extra approvals, reports and meetings. They are also restricting the people you need from working on your project in a larger capacity. What will you do next?",
    A: "Go directly to the people you need to avoid extra back-and-forth with the stakeholders.",
    B: "Raise a risk in the risk register on the lack of access to sufficient resources.",
    C: "Communicate more often with the stakeholders and gain a deeper awareness of their ideas and situation.",
    D: "Show your stakeholders the Resource Assignment Matrix and project roles & responsibilities.",
    Answer: "Communicate more often with the stakeholders and gain a deeper awareness of their ideas and situation.",
    Reason: "This question refers to the principle of Effectively Engaging with Stakeholders. Stakeholders may add steps or requirements, or restrict team members if not engaged appropriately. Communication and awareness of their ideas, through knowledge sharing and regular meetings (ideally face-to-face) help."
  },
  {
    ID: "54",
    Question: "You are managing a project team mostly made up of men. Recently Jane was hired for her high expertise in the brands that make up your industry. You notice she has been left out of some key meetings, and others are overlooking her opinions. You also notice she is paid significantly less than her male colleagues. What will you do next?",
    A: "Make steps to update her pay to the same range as the others on your project, and ask her opinion and advice specifically during each meeting (along with others in your team).",
    B: "Make the lower pay as a win for your project, as it will help keep costs low and her colleagues don't need to know.",
    C: "Ask Jane to write down her knowledge of the industry, just in case she leaves.",
    D: "No need to rock the boat - this is just how people work in this industry.",
    Answer: "Make steps to update her pay to the same range as the others on your project, and ask her opinion and advice specifically during each meeting (along with others in your team).",
    Reason: "The question is on Integrity and Stewardship. We should have respectful engagement of project team members, including their compensation, access to opportunity and fair treatment."
  },
  {
    ID: "55",
    Question: "During one of your working group meetings, a stakeholder raises the concern that the product you are working on will be discontinued in the next five months. You were not aware of this, and your project budget has already been approved until the scheduled delivery, which is in five month also. What will you do next?",
    A: "Keep the project going as it is - the discontinued product isn't your responsibility.",
    B: "Set a meeting with your project sponsor to share the information and a recommendation to terminate the project.",
    C: "Change the scope of the project to meet a different product so your project can remain relevant.",
    D: "Ask for additional funding to see if you can improve the product instead of discontinuing it.",
    Answer: "Set a meeting with your project sponsor to share the information and a recommendation to terminate the project.",
    Reason: "This question is about delivering value - the primary motivator for a project. If the project is no longer aligned with the business need or it seems unlikely to provide value, the organization may choose to terminate the effort."
  },
  {
    ID: "56",
    Question: "You have collected the requirements for your project and are creating the scope statement and work breakdown structure (WBS). During this process you notice some functionality in your database system that will help a different project you are aware of within your Project Management Office (PMO). What will you do next?",
    A: "Place the feature in the other project's backlog, and ask them to prioritize it as soon as possible.",
    B: "Raise the functionality in your risk register as a threat, with the response to mitigate.",
    C: "Add the scope to your project and complete it as soon as possible.",
    D: "Raise the functionality in your risk register as an opportunity with the response to exploit, and meet with the other project team and sponsor to discuss.",
    Answer: "Raise the functionality in your risk register as an opportunity with the response to exploit, and meet with the other project team and sponsor to discuss.",
    Reason: "Systems thinking involves taking a holistic view of how project parts interact with each other, and external systems. Project operate within programs, and small systems affect larger ones. Finding a previously unknown opportunity, the next best step is to make it known and exploit the opportunity."
  },
  {
    ID: "57",
    Question: "You are working on a high-profile project. Several high-ranking senior executives want to take the credit for this initiative, while limiting the impact to their own reseources. This has led to several conflicts and a scope statement that is unclear, leading to a risk of project failure. What will you do next?",
    A: "Create a scope statement yourself to avoid further conflict.",
    B: "Facilitate a discussion with the executives as a neutral third party, focusing on agreed project goals.",
    C: "Limit your project resources to the executives until they can agree on a way forward.",
    D: "Escalate the issue to the steering committee and ask them to resolve the problem.",
    Answer: "Facilitate a discussion with the executives as a neutral third party, focusing on agreed project goals.",
    Reason: "Leadership is not the same as authority. When senior managers suffer conflict over priorities, neutral facilitation helps more than detailed recommendations. Leadership acumen involves focusing a team around agreed goals, generating consensus on the way forward, negotiating and resolving conflict, and more."
  },
  {
    ID: "58",
    Question: "You are managing a project where the majority of the product has been planned up-front but an external system is needed from a vendor in partial pieces where the requirements are unclear. Half of your stakeholders want to use a waterfall approach, and the other half are advocating for an Agile approach. What will you do next?",
    A: "Use an Agile methodology. The fixed scope is low risk, and you can capture changes using Agile.",
    B: "Use a Waterfall methodology and ask the team to plan the uncertain scope better.",
    C: "Proceed with a hybrid method to start, with pre-planned scope but Agile ceremonies that promote feedback.",
    D: "Use a combination of Waterfall and Agile to capture all the requirements and keep stakeholders happy.",
    Answer: "Proceed with a hybrid method to start, with pre-planned scope but Agile ceremonies that promote feedback.",
    Reason: "Each project is unique, and success is based on adapting to the unique context of the project to determine the most appropriate methods. The tailoring approach is iterative in nature and refined during the project cycle. This project requires a hybrid of Waterfall and Agile, with the option to improve it over time."
  },
  {
    ID: "59",
    Question: "You are working on a project where senior users have been testing the product as parts are released. They have found some missing requirements and defects. Their manager is worried that the project won't deliver a product that is fit for purpose, without defects and within the timeframe needed. What will you do next?",
    A: "Perform some of the testing yourself to ensure a quality product.",
    B: "Help every team member to focus on quality, from correct acceptance criteria to a developed and tested product.",
    C: "Limit testing until the very end of the project so you can do it all in one go when the product is completely ready.",
    D: "Increase the testing on your project and add more testing resources so no defect goes unnoticed.",
    Answer: "Help every team member to focus on quality, from correct acceptance criteria to a developed and tested product.",
    Reason: "Quality focuses on meeting acceptance criteria for deliverables, and satisfying stakeholders' expectations on product requirements. Quality is everyone's responsibility in an Adaptive (Agile) project."
  },
  {
    ID: "60",
    Question: "You are working through the risk assessment with your team, who are having trouble coming up with ideas for risks. You decide to give them some guidance on types of complexity that might affect your new product. What will you do next?",
    A: "Ask them to brainstorm Qualitative and Quantitative risks.",
    B: "Ask them to perform the Five Whys and Ishikawa analysis.",
    C: "Ask them to brainstorm around possible unwanted human behaviour, system behaviour, ambiguity and technical innovation impacts.",
    D: "Ask them to perform a retrospective to discover what isn't working well, and what still puzzles us.",
    Answer: "Ask them to brainstorm around possible unwanted human behaviour, system behaviour, ambiguity and technical innovation impacts.",
    Reason: "Complexity is often the result of human behaviour, system interactions, technical innovation, uncertainty and ambiguity. Complexity can be introduced by events or conditions that affect value, scope, stakeholders, risk and more."
  },
  {
    ID: "61",
    Question: "You are working on a project where you discover a certain negative risk with a potential impact of $2,000,000. You meet with your project stakeholders who determine that this is within their risk appetite, provided you meet a risk threshold of 10%. What will you do next?",
    A: "Note the acceptable risk level as a threat of $200,00 (10%).",
    B: "Note the acceptable risk level as a threat of $1,800,000 to $2,200,000 (10% variance).",
    C: "Note the impact as outside the acceptable risk level of $2,000,000.",
    D: "Note the impact as an opportunity of $200,000 (10%).",
    Answer: "Note the acceptable risk level as a threat of $1,800,000 to $2,200,000 (10% variance).",
    Reason: "Risk appetite describes the level of uncertainty or risk your stakeholders are willing to accept. Risk threshold is the measure of acceptable variation around an objective that reflects the risk appetite. In this scenario a 10% variation around $2m is $1.8m to $2.2m."
  },
  {
    ID: "62",
    Question: "A risk has been raised in your project around insufficient building material. One risk response assigned to the functional manager suggests to use a brand new material, which has not been fully tested in a building project. Half of your stakeholder group are happy with this risk response, but the other half are not, and refuse to sign off on it. What will you do next?",
    A: "Suggest a quantitative risk approach to give a more accurate financial impact.",
    B: "Suggest they proceed with the proposed risk response, and ensure it is followed through.",
    C: "Suggest a different risk owner, as an executive may have more power to respond to the risk.",
    D: "Suggest a different risk response, as they should be timely, cost effective, realistic, and agreed to by relevant stakeholders.",
    Answer: "Suggest a different risk response, as they should be timely, cost effective, realistic, and agreed to by relevant stakeholders.",
    Reason: "This question refers to risk responses. Risk responses should be appropriate and timely to the significance of the risk, cost effective, realistic within the project context, agreed to by relevant stakeholders, and owned by a responsible person."
  },
  {
    ID: "63",
    Question: "Your project is starting to go off track due to a large amount of uncertainty in the requirements and resources. At a significant cost, you have managed to reign in these issues, however your project management office would like you to brainstrom ways to improve with your team so that they do not happen again. What will you do next?",
    A: "Ask your team to increase the project Contingency Reserve, to allow for these impacts.",
    B: "Ask your team to change the project methodology from Waterfall to Agile.",
    C: "Ask your team to use short feedback loops, continuous improvement, and transparent planning.",
    D: "Ask your team to check their work twice before sending it to the next part of the process.",
    Answer: "Ask your team to use short feedback loops, continuous improvement, and transparent planning.",
    Reason: "A project team needs to embrace adaptability and resiliency with methods such as using short feedback loops, continuous learning and improvement, regular inspection and adaptation of project work, diverse project teams, transparent planning, using prototypes and more."
  },
  {
    ID: "64",
    Question: "As your project progresses, many of the business stakeholders are starting to voice their conerns, to question some of the changes, and even miss key meetings while trying to sabotage your efforts. What will you do next?",
    A: "Communicate the vision and benefits for the change clearly, along with the impact to their work.",
    B: "Create an impact over influence chart to determine who should be engaged appropriately.",
    C: "Escalate the matter with your project sponsor, and arrange for different stakeholders.",
    D: "Map the current state and the proposed future state of the change for the stakeholders.",
    Answer: "Communicate the vision and benefits for the change clearly, along with the impact to their work.",
    Reason: "The question is on change management, which is a structured approach to transitioning groups to a future state. Too much change or lack of understanding can lead to resistance and change fatigue. Methods include communicating the vision, goals and benefits of the change early, along with the impact to work processes."
  },
  {
    ID: "65",
    Question: "You are analyzing your stakeholders through an impact over influence chart and have found more than 100 different groups of people, and over 3000 impacted stakeholders. Other parts of your project are starting to fall behind as you try to keep up with the large amount of people. What will you do next?",
    A: "Ask your team to engage different groups of stakeholders so everyone is covered.",
    B: "Clearly prioritize the stakeholders then engage and communicate with the highly impacted and influential groups early and often.",
    C: "Monitor the stakeholders for signs of stress and respond to groups most stressed about the project.",
    D: "Create a SharePoint page for changes that any stakeholder can gather information from anytime.",
    Answer: "Clearly prioritize the stakeholders then engage and communicate with the highly impacted and influential groups early and often.",
    Reason: "This question is about engaging stakeholders. The process includes: Identify, Understand and Analyze, Priotize, Engage and Monitor your stakeholders. Where you have too many to engage effectively, prioritization is the key. Impact and Influence are two ways, as well as Power, Beliefs, Expectations, proximity to the project, interest and more."
  },
  {
    ID: "66",
    Question: "You are managing a project with communicates to the customer using mostly pull communication so far. When monitoring the engagement of your stakeholders, you notice a trend that they are not clear on the impacts or benefits of the project. You decide to add push communication to your communication plan. What will you do next?",
    A: "Create a webpage using SharePoint with all the project information, that your stakeholders can see.",
    B: "Push for more funding on your project, and communicate this to your project sponsor.",
    C: "Push your stakeholders to engage in more two-way communication.",
    D: "Send a weekly email to stakeholders with a project update, including the impacts and benefits.",
    Answer: "Send a weekly email to stakeholders with a project update, including the impacts and benefits.",
    Reason: "Push communication is sent to stakeholders, using memos, emails, status reports, voice mail and more. Pull communication is something a customer can pull at any time - from a bulletin, a webpage, a white board, etc."
  },
  {
    ID: "67",
    Question: "You have taken over a project with a vendor where scope and requirements have been missed. You notice that miscommunication and mixed messages are common. You set a meeting with your team and the vendor's team. The meeting is extremely important to get right. What will you do next?",
    A: "Speak slowly and clearly with the vendor's team, at a louder volume if necessary.",
    B: "Confirm they hear your message, determine if they agree, and identify nuanced or unintended messages they may have received.",
    C: "Only communicate with the vendor in writing, so you have a trail of proof if anything goes wrong in the future.",
    D: "Prepare a claim for the mishandled scope of your project through your procurement team.",
    Answer: "Confirm they hear your message, determine if they agree, and identify nuanced or unintended messages they may have received.",
    Reason: "This question is asking about communication. With all forms of communication, quick feedback loops provide the information you need by confirming they heard the message, determining if they agree, and identifying any nuances or additions to the message they may have added or heard."
  },
  {
    ID: "68",
    Question: "Your stakeholders seem to be engaged, however there are frequent changes to scope and requirements, causing delays. Issues are often raised and result in multiple rounds of feedback. You are not sure who or what could be the cause. What will you do next?",
    A: "Perform root cause analysis with your project team on the problem to brainstorm ideas.",
    B: "Raise a risk in the risk register for the project delay, and review responses with your team.",
    C: "Review the issue log, risk register and change log for the most frequent requestors, then update your stakeholder engagement approach for those people.",
    D: "Ensure your project budget has enough contingency reserves to meet the multiple review and delays.",
    Answer: "Review the issue log, risk register and change log for the most frequent requestors, then update your stakeholder engagement approach for those people.",
    Reason: "A significant number for changes or modifications to the project requirements or scope may indicate stakeholders are not engaged or aligned with the project objectives. A review of the project issue register or risk register can identify challenges associated with individual stakeholders."
  },
  {
    ID: "69",
    Question: "You have been working on a project where the manager leads in a dictatorship style. Over time, the team have stopped making suggestions, sick days and mental health days have become more frequent, and the pace of work has slowed. The manager comes to you for help. You suggest a servant leadership style instead. What will they do next?",
    A: "Serve the team as much as they can, ensuring their every need is met.",
    B: "Focus on obstacle removal, encouragement and development opportunities.",
    C: "Ensure their team are serving other team members and helping each other succeed.",
    D: "Server the team new ways to do the work and engage them through additional variety.",
    Answer: "Server the team new ways to do the work and engage them through additional variety.",
    Reason: "Servant leaders allow project teams to self-organize when possible, and increase levels of autonomy by passing appropriate decision making opportunities to project team members. Servant leadership behaviours also include obstacle removal, being a diversion shield, and development opportunities."
  },
  {
    ID: "70",
    Question: "You have been allocated to a new project team with members from different parts of the functional business area. It soon becomes clear that very few of them have worked on a project before. There is also a lot of miscommunication and re-work occurring amongst the team, which is start to cause delays. What will you do next?",
    A: "Set a daily stand-up with your team to ensure they update what they completed.",
    B: "Review the Resource Assignment Matrix with your team and ensure they are doing their job.",
    C: "Help the team set their vision and objectives, roles and responsibilities, and team operations.",
    D: "Send your team members on training in their roles to increase their capability.",
    Answer: "Help the team set their vision and objectives, roles and responsibilities, and team operations.",
    Reason: "When project teams form across different organizations, more work may be required up front to establish a one-team mindset, ensuring everyone understands how they contribute. Team development such as establishing a vision, clear roles & responsibilities, and a way of working are key."
  },
  {
    ID: "71",
    Question: "You have collected requirement for your project, matched them to project scope, and broken them down into smaller parts and the activities required. In doing this, you notice that the manager of the marketing department has added extra scope that is unrelated to your current project. What will you do next?",
    A: "Start and open dialogue with the functional manager, raise the incorrect scope items and their impacts.",
    B: "Override the marketing manager's decision on scope as you are the senior project manager.",
    C: "Raise a change request for the additional scope and let the Change Control Board decide.",
    D: "Place the additional scope into the product backlog for the product owner to prioritize it.",
    Answer: "Start and open dialogue with the functional manager, raise the incorrect scope items and their impacts.",
    Reason: "Without an open dialogue, you may not know if the scope was a mistake, previously approved, or any other reason for it being there. Positive discourse and courage are key aspects of a winning project team culture. Others include support, respect, celebrating success, and transparency."
  },
  {
    ID: "72",
    Question: "Your project team are protected by a union agreement. You notice that they don't know how to use the product you are improving, are slow to respond and regularly complain about the work. Your project sponsor has had enough and threatens to shut the project down if improvement can't be made. What will you do next?",
    A: "Set up a new project with different team members and transfer the project work to that team.",
    B: "Set a clear project and vision and pair your team with the customer to show them how they are making a positive difference.",
    C: "Tell your project team that they will lose their jobs if they don't improve the speed of their work.",
    D: "Create a project Gantt Chart schedule and burndown chart so the project work is transparent to all.",
    Answer: "Set a clear project and vision and pair your team with the customer to show them how they are making a positive difference.",
    Reason: "This question calls for leadership skills, where setting a vision and purpose and showing your team how they are making a difference can increase their intrinsic motivation. Transferring to another team in the same company may risk the same result, and threatening your team may embed their behaviour further."
  },
  {
    ID: "73",
    Question: "During a key scope meeting, an argument arises. The business manager accuses the technology manager of not delivering to their needs on past projects, and the technology manager accuses the business manager of changing requirement that impact the dilivery schedule. The meeting is at risk, with the stakeholders being closed off to any further discussion. What will you do next?",
    A: "Take the side of the technology manager, as scope that impacts delivery should be controlled.",
    B: "Take the side of the business manager, as we should always deliver to the customer's specificiation.",
    C: "Facilitate to keep communication respectful, focus on the issue in the present and search for alternatives together.",
    D: "Ensure they both agree to the change control process to avoid disagreements in the future.",
    Answer: "Facilitate to keep communication respectful, focus on the issue in the present and search for alternatives together.",
    Reason: "Not all conflict is negative. How conflict is handled can either lead to more conflict or to better decision making and stronger solutions. The PMBOK Guide notes open and respectful communication, focusing on the issue not the person, the present not the past, and searching for alternatives together."
  },
  {
    ID: "74",
    Question: "You are working on a project where the project team is completely distributed around the country in multiple sites, including working from home. Some of the project team members have not been able to contribute to the project, and there are concerns from the program that the project will fall behind. What will you do next?",
    A: "Raise a request to the program to co-locate all your project team members as soon as possible.",
    B: "Proceed with daily stand-ups and working group meetings with any team members in your area.",
    C: "Set team leaders for each area around the country, to report back to you as the centralized project leader.",
    D: "Use technology to maintain ongoing contact with audio and video for meetings, with a team web site to keep all project information available.",
    Answer: "Use technology to maintain ongoing contact with audio and video for meetings, with a team web site to keep all project information available.",
    Reason: "This question is on distributed project teams. To improve you can use audio and video capabilities for meetings, use technology (including messaging) for ongoing contact, build in time to get to know remote team members, and have an open project site for information."
  },
  {
    ID: "75",
    Question: "You are initiating a project to a sales team where the process will change significantly, even though the outcome of a completed sale will remain the same. The functional manager is concerned about the change and any disruption it might bring. What will you do next?",
    A: "Kick off the project with multiple deliveries to deliver small parts and reduce the change impact.",
    B: "Kick off the project work with a single delivery at the end of the project when the process change is complete.",
    C: "Kick off the project with continuous delivery in mide, to ensure fast value to the business.",
    D: "Kick off the project using periodic deliveries, delivering value as it is ready.",
    Answer: "Kick off the project work with a single delivery at the end of the project when the process change is complete.",
    Reason: "This question covers delivery cadence and their various benefits. A process re-engineering project may not have any deliveries until near the end of the project when the new process is rolled out and ready."
  },
  {
    ID: "76",
    Question: "You are working on a project where the requirements are clear but the solution ideas are uncertain. The product owner and the technical experts can't be sure which ideas will work in practice, and which ones won't. The organization cannot afford to get this project wrong, as they have previously made mistakes and customers are starting to leave. What will you do next?",
    A: "Use and Incremental development approach for the project.",
    B: "Use an Iterative development approach for the project.",
    C: "Use a predictive development approach for the project.",
    D: "Use a hybrid development approach for the project.",
    Answer: "Use an Iterative development approach for the project.",
    Reason: "For development approaches, an interative approach is used when you need to capture ideas that might change, while still delivered in one release. Incremental progressively delivers features (or increments), Predictive plans everything up-front, and hybrid is a combination of predictive and adaptive."
  },
  {
    ID: "77",
    Question: "You are working on a new product for your organization where the requirements are complex and are likely to change a few times as the project progresses. The organization also needs usable parts of the product to be release as soon as possible to try and capture some of the market they are aiming for, away from their competitors. What will you do next?",
    A: "Recommend an Iterative development approach.",
    B: "Recommend a Predictive development approach.",
    C: "Recommend an Adaptive development approach.",
    D: "Recommend a Hybrid development approach.",
    Answer: "Recommend an Adaptive development approach.",
    Reason: "Adaptive approaches are useful when requirements are subject to uncertainty and change. A clear vision is established at the start of the project, and initial known requirements are refined or replaced in accordance with user feedback or unexpected events."
  },
  {
    ID: "78",
    Question: "A new project has been kicked off in your organization due to a recent government inquiry into your industry, which found multiple processes with significant regulatory oversight that need to change. The inquiry ordering these changes has given you a due date of 10 months' time before you start incurring penalties. What will you do next?",
    A: "Proceed, with an Agile development approach to deliver change as quickly as possible.",
    B: "Proceed, with a Hybrid development approach to respond to changes while planning up front.",
    C: "Proceed, with a Predictive methodology to ensure quality control.",
    D: "Proceed, with an Iterative methodology to improve using feedback.",
    Answer: "Proceed, with a Predictive methodology to ensure quality control.",
    Reason: "In considerations for selecting a development approach, environments that have significant regulatory oversight may need to use a predictive approach due to the require process, documentation and demonstration needs."
  },
  {
    ID: "79",
    Question: "Your organization is moving to an Agile way of work. Your project team are strongly opposed to using Agile as they have been burned using iterations, when executives used the team velocity to try and force the team to work faster instead of keeping a sustainable pace. What will you do next?",
    A: "Add extra resources to your team to deliver faster and avoid executives getting involved.",
    B: "Proceed with a predictive development approach, and deal with the consequences later.",
    C: "Ask your team to work with Agile, velocity and iterations despite their hesitations.",
    D: "Suggest the team uses flow-based scheduling, with a Kanban board for visual work.",
    Answer: "Suggest the team uses flow-based scheduling, with a Kanban board for visual work.",
    Reason: "Kanban is one of the largest parts of Agile approaches, aside from other major parts such as Lean, XP and Scrum. A flow-based scheduling approach does not use sprints, lifecycles or velocity but optimises deliveries based on resource capacity, and minimizes waste such as context-switching and hand-offs."
  },
  {
    ID: "80",
    Question: "Your team have not worked on projects before, and don't know about Waterfall, Agile, or any of the different models. Your project may also have requirements that are certain or uncertain, with varying levels of risk, so are not sure which approach to use as you begin this new project. What will you do next?",
    A: "Use Waterfall and plan everything up front, so the team have more stability.",
    B: "Use general phase definitions such as Feasibility, Design, Build, Test, Deploy and Close.",
    C: "Use Agile to ensure you can respond to change while your team's capability increases.",
    D: "Don't use any project approach - it doesn't matter as long as the work is getting done.",
    Answer: "Use general phase definitions such as Feasibility, Design, Build, Test, Deploy and Close.",
    Reason: "All projects will go through the general phases of Feasibility, Design, Build, Test, Deploy and Close. Waterfall projects will do these in sequence once, while Agile projects will do these multiple times, for each feature or increment. The underlying principle remains the same, so it is a good place to start."
  },
  {
    ID: "81",
    Question: "You are a project manager in an organization with a directive Project Management Office (PMO), and are currently in between projects. The PMO asks you to prepare for an upcoming project in the accounting area by meeting with the functional manager there. You have no team, no scope or requirements and no timeline as of yet. What will you do next?",
    A: "Ask the functional manager for their wish-list of improvements, so you can take these to your PMO.",
    B: "Create a project management plan so the project, scope, budget and schedule are more clear.",
    C: "Create a small backlog of work and start your first sprint, then progressively update the backlog as the project progresses.",
    D: "Progressively elaborate the vision statement and project charter to define a coordinated approach.",
    Answer: "Progressively elaborate the vision statement and project charter to define a coordinated approach.",
    Reason: "Before initiating a project of any sort, we start with a vision statement, project charter or business case in order to identify a coordinated path to achieve the desired outcomes."
  },
  {
    ID: "82",
    Question: "You are working on a project where part of the project delivers a high value, high risk component. Another part of the project delivers a routine change to the system. Your project sponsor wants to gain the business value as quickly as possible, but your project team want to start with the work they are familiar with first. What will you do next?",
    A: "Prioritize the high risk items at the end of the project.",
    B: "Prioritize the high risk items at the start of the project.",
    C: "Use an incremental approach and deliver part of the routine and high risk work in each sprint.",
    D: "Plan out the work in detail and secure a scope baseline, with formal change controls to reduce uncertainty.",
    Answer: "Prioritize the high risk items at the start of the project.",
    Reason: "This question refers to the concept of the last responsible moment. Work that is novel or risky can be prioritized at the start of the project to reduce uncertainty with the project scope before a large investment has been made. Routine work can be delayed until the cost of further delay would exceed the benefit."
  },
  {
    ID: "83",
    Question: "You are working on an agile project where the functional area you are delivering to only has a high level idea of the system requirements they will need. The function manager suggests a Work Breakdown Structure (WBS), however your team feel that is more for a predictive (Waterfall) delivery approach. What will you do next?",
    A: "Use and create a WBS anyway, as it is just a tool.",
    B: "Use rolling wave planning, and keep the work at a high level until you are ready to work on it, when you can plan in detail.",
    C: "Note the high-level themes or epics, decompose them into features, and again into user stories.",
    D: "Ask the functional area for more detailed requirements before the project begins.",
    Answer: "Note the high-level themes or epics, decompose them into features, and again into user stories.",
    Reason: "This question refers to decomposition or breaking down the work. We could use a WBS, or rolling wave planning, but for an incremental approach breaking down the work from epics to features to user stories is a form of decomposition that fits the delivery approach."
  },
  {
    ID: "84",
    Question: "You are at the beginning of planning a new project, and have researched and gathered the requirements from the area, broken them down into deliverables and activities, which you believe could take 26 weeks to deliver. The project sponsor is asking you for an estimate on how long the project will take. What will you do next?",
    A: "Tell the project sponsor 26 weeks.",
    B: "Tell the project sponsor that you will use an iterative approach, where value is delivered until the project stops.",
    C: "Tell the project sponsor approximately 24 to 28 weeks.",
    D: "Tell the project sponsor approximately 20 to 45 weeks.",
    Answer: "Tell the project sponsor approximately 20 to 45 weeks.",
    Reason: "This question is related to estimation and range. Estimates should have a broad range at the start of the project, starting at -25% to +75% when there is not much information. Once the project team has a smooth delivery cadence and experience in the product, a smaller range such as -5% to +10% can be used. A 0% range is when everything is known and the product has been delivered."
  },
  {
    ID: "85",
    Question: "After gathering your project requirements, project scope, and breaking it down into activities, you need to estimate the project schedule with your team. After some analysis and discussion, your team come with with a range of 53 to 75 days assigned across all tasks. What will you do next?",
    A: "The estimate is high accuracy but low precision - ask the team to come back with a more precise estimate.",
    B: "The estimate is low accuracy but high precision - ensure the estimates become more accurate as the project unfolds.",
    C: "The estimate is in high confidence but low precision - proceed as is and adjust using an incremental approach.",
    D: "The estimate is in low confidence but high accuracy - allow the team to become more confident as the project unfolds.",
    Answer: "The estimate is low accuracy but high precision - ensure the estimates become more accurate as the project unfolds.",
    Reason: "This question is on estimates and their accuracy. The lower the accuracy, the larger the potential range in values. Precision is different from accuracy, as it refers to the exactness of the estimate, for example, 2 days is more precise than sometime this week."
  },
  {
    ID: "86",
    Question: "You are working on a business case where you know that the industry is undergoing a significant change at the moment, and there could be many different impact to your project benefits before it is delivered completely. The project sponsor asks you for the best estimate of benefits you can give under the circumstances. What will you do next?",
    A: "Ask your team for a probabilistic estimate.",
    B: "Ask for your team for a deterministic estimate.",
    C: "Ask for your team for an absolute estimate.",
    D: "Ask your team for a relative estimate.",
    Answer: "Ask your team for a probabilistic estimate.",
    Reason: "Probabilistic estimates include a range of estimates, along with the associated probabilities within the range such as a confidence level or a probability distribution. If the estimate is uncertain, this is the best approach. Deterministic is a number, absolute is specific, actual numbers and relative estimates are shown in comparison to other estimates."
  },
  {
    ID: "87",
    Question: "You have noted nine epics for delivery as part of your most recent project. Your team have broken down these epics into user stories, and would like to see the effort involved for these deliverables. You ask your team to find the smallest user story, size it with a 1, and then determine the size of the other cards based on how they compare to the original card. What approach are you taking?",
    A: "Relative estimating with your team.",
    B: "Deterministic estimating to determine the effort.",
    C: "Absolute estimating to get an estimate with absolute certainty.",
    D: "Probabilistic estimating with the highest probability items.",
    Answer: "Relative estimating with your team.",
    Reason: "This question is about estimating, and making an estimate in comparison to other estimates is relative estimating."
  },
  {
    ID: "88",
    Question: "You are working on a project where a competitor is also working on a similar feature, and being first to the market will have a significant impact on this year's profit. Your product owner would like to measure how quickly story cards are being completed, once they start being developed. What will you do next?",
    A: "Check the Lead time of the story cards.",
    B: "Check the Gantt chart with assigned schedule activities.",
    C: "Check the cycle time of the story cards.",
    D: "Check the schedule network and precedence diagram.",
    Answer: "Check the cycle time of the story cards.",
    Reason: "Cycle time is the total elapsed time it takes one unit to get through a process. Lead time is the time from when the customer makes the order (or the requirement is noted) to the time the item is delivered or released. Schedule network diagram is useful for finding the Critical Path, and precedence diagramming is used to find what deliverable or activity release on others."
  },
  {
    ID: "89",
    Question: "You are working on a project that has recently moved to a more agile way of work. The team have not completely taken on the Scrum approach however, and are comfortable working with a more flow-based approach moving user stories across a Kanban board. You are wanting to get an estimate on how much work can be completed in the next three months, based on the team's existing progress. What will you do next?",
    A: "Multiply the velocity by the number of remaining user stories.",
    B: "Multiply the cycle time by the throughput.",
    C: "Multiply the lead time by the schedule performance index.",
    D: "Multiply the planned value by the actual value.",
    Answer: "Multiply the cycle time by the throughput.",
    Reason: "Scrum uses velocity - Kanban or Flow-based estimates are developed by determining the cycle time and throughput. Cycle time is the total elapsed time it takes one unit to get through a process. Throughput is the number of items that can complete a process in a given amount of time."
  },
  {
    ID: "90",
    Question: "Your product owner wants to bring the next feature forward so that it is done in parallel to the current feature, but is still released in the existing feature order. You make the necessary adjustments to the product backlog, and decide to adjust the product roadmap, which you have visualized as a Gantt chart. What will you do next?",
    A: "Use a schedule lead on the feature, and change the feature to finish-to-start.",
    B: "Use a schedule lag on the feature, and change the feature to start to start.",
    C: "Use a schedule lead on the feature, and change the feature to finish-to-finish.",
    D: "Use a schedule lag on the feature, and change the feature to start-to-finish.",
    Answer: "Use a schedule lead on the feature, and change the feature to finish-to-finish.",
    Reason: "A schedule lag is moving an item back, a schedule lead is bringing an item forward. Precedence diagramming method states for Finish-to-finish items, the next item cannot finish until the previous item has finished. This allows the items to be worked on in parallel, while still keeping the same delivery order."
  },
  {
    ID: "91",
    Question: "You are working on a project where you have been completeing the deliverables in sequence, and the project work is starting to fall behind. The project sponsor asks you to speed up the work and reduce the time for the project to be delivered, but also makes it very clear that there is no more money to use when speeding up the work. What will you do next?",
    A: "Apply leads and lags to your project schedule.",
    B: "Apply fast tracking to your project schedule.",
    C: "Apply schedule crashing to your project.",
    D: "Apply resource levelling to your project.",
    Answer: "Apply fast tracking to your project schedule.",
    Reason: "Project fast-tracking is a schedule compression method in which activities or tasks that are normally done in sequence are performed in parallel. Schedule crashing includes adding people to activities, working overtime, or paying to expedite deliveries."
  },
  {
    ID: "92",
    Question: "After reviewing your project schedule you notice you are behind by three weeks and the schedule will need to be compressed. Your project does not have enough budget to crash the schedule. You check with the lead for each eare and review the schedule as to whether they can fast-track their deliverables. What will you do next?",
    A: "Fast-track team items with discretionary dependencies.",
    B: "Fast-track team items with mandatory dependencies.",
    C: "Fast-track team items with external dependencies.",
    D: "Fast-track team items based on industry regulation.",
    Answer: "Fast-track team items with discretionary dependencies.",
    Reason: "When compressing the schedule, some activities cannot be fast-tracked because of the nature of the work, others can. A discretionary dependency is based on project preferences, and may be modifiable. External and Mandatory dependencies usually cannot be modified. Internal dependencies may be modifiable, except when based on specific regulatory needs."
  },
  {
    ID: "93",
    Question: "Your team are new to Agile, and had previously been working with Waterfall. Your key customer asks you for a project schedule. The project team believes using a project schedule is from the old Waterfall way of working and they shouldn't have to create one. What will you do next?",
    A: "Create a project Gantt chart to visualize the activities within the project.",
    B: "Determine the project's planned versus actual value, instead of working with a schedule directly.",
    C: "Advise the customer that we don't need to plan ahead in an adaptive way of work.",
    D: "Ask your team to develop a high level release plan like a product roadmap, showing the features to be included in each release.",
    Answer: "Ask your team to develop a high level release plan like a product roadmap, showing the features to be included in each release.",
    Reason: "Adaptive schedule planning uses incremental planning. A high level release plan is developed that indicates basic features and functionalitity to be included in each release."
  },
  {
    ID: "94",
    Question: "You are working in a project team that has recently moved to an Agile way of work. Your business analysts want to gather the requirements, solutions, match them to the scope and do a work breakdown structure (WBS) for the whole deliverable. Your product owner says this will take too long, and is not Agile enough for their needs. What will you do next?",
    A: "Ask your team to review the scope management plan for the proper process.",
    B: "Break the deliverable down into smaller pieces so you can deliver those faster.",
    C: "Ask your team to timebox work on the highest priority items in the backlog, update the estimates then reprioritize as necessary.",
    D: "Review the project charter for the high level scope, and use this to begin delivery quickly.",
    Answer: "Ask your team to timebox work on the highest priority items in the backlog, update the estimates then reprioritize as necessary.",
    Reason: "Adaptive approaches often use timeboxes. The work is based on a prioritized backlog. The project team determines the amount of work they can do in each timebox, estimates the work and self-manages to accomplish the work. At this point, the backlog may be reprioritized for the next timebox."
  },
  {
    ID: "95",
    Question: "When reviewing the current progress with your project sponsor, they notice that the system solution is missing a critical piece that will impact the benefit of the project. The project sponsor approves this scope. Your project has a Planned Value of $520,000 and an Actual Cost of $535,000. What will you do next?",
    A: "Work with the Project Management Office (PMO) to unlock the project management reserves for the extra work.",
    B: "Ask the product owner to reprioritize the backlog and see if the new work will fit.",
    C: "Perform the work within your normal budget as your project is on track.",
    D: "Raise a change request for the changes and gain approval from the Change Control Board.",
    Answer: "Work with the Project Management Office (PMO) to unlock the project management reserves for the extra work.",
    Reason: "Management reserves are set aside for unexpected activities related to in-scope work. Depending on the organization's policies, management reserves may be managed by the PMO at the program or portfolio level."
  },
  {
    ID: "96",
    Question: "You are in the planning stages of an Agile project where the functional manager and senior users have provided the high level requirements and scope. You have been asked to put together a project team that will be able to deliver quickly. What will you do next?",
    A: "Select project members from each city to ensure diversity of knowledge within the team.",
    B: "Put together a resource management plan outline the resources required.",
    C: "Ask your PMO for current available resources and assign them to the work.",
    D: "Select a small team that can work in the same area so they can solve problems as they arise.",
    Answer: "Select a small team that can work in the same area so they can solve problems as they arise.",
    Reason: "When planning for the team, the project manager considers the ability and necessity for them to work in the same location. Small project teams that can work in the same room are able to take advantage of osmotic communication and can solve problems as they arise."
  },
  {
    ID: "97",
    Question: "You are putting together a project team to deliver an accounting system to offices around the country. The accounting system you are moving to has not been used by anyone in your organization before. The project is quite high risk, and the delivery needs to be right the first time. What will you do next?",
    A: "Select a small team that can work in the same area so they can solve problems as they arise.",
    B: "Use a predictive project approach and source part of your team externally if they have skillsets in the new system.",
    C: "Train existing internal staff in the new system then have them work on the project.",
    D: "Perform a make or buy analysis on the different software options.",
    Answer: "Use a predictive project approach and source part of your team externally if they have skillsets in the new system.",
    Reason: "The benefit that outside skills bring to the project are weighed against the costs that will be incurred. With higher risk and a single delivery, a Waterfall or predictive project delivery approach is best."
  },
  {
    ID: "98",
    Question: "You are putting together a project plan for a change that affects nearly ten thousand stakeholders in your organization. You have identified the affect stakeholders, analyzed and prioritized them, and are putting together a communication plan to ensure the right engagement is made. What will you NOT include in your plan?",
    A: "Why should information be shared with stakeholders?",
    B: "What is the best way to provide information?",
    C: "How can they make changes to the communication plan?",
    D: "When and how often is information needed?",
    Answer: "How can they make changes to the communication plan?",
    Reason: "Planning communication for the project entails considering the following: Who needs the information? Who has the information needed? Why should information be shared with stakeholder? When and how often is information needed? What is the best way to provide information? What information does each stakeholder need?"
  },
  {
    ID: "99",
    Question: "You put together a resource plan for a large amount of physical inventory to be purchased from overseas. You ordered the inventory during project execution, however global supply chains were impacted and the shipment was delayed by three months, significantly impacting your project. What should you have done differently?",
    A: "Hired a resource manager to take care of the resource tasks on your project.",
    B: "Planned strategically about the timing from order to delivery to usage, managing resource risks and their responses.",
    C: "Ensured a means to track the inventory from arrival on site to the delivery of an integrated product.",
    D: "Sourced the inventory locally to reduce the impact of global supply chains.",
    Answer: "Planned strategically about the timing from order to delivery to usage, managing resource risks and their responses.",
    Reason: "Project teams whose projects require significant physical materials think and plan strategically about the timing from order, to delivery, to usage. This can include evaluation of bulk ordering versus the cost of storage, global logistics and more."
  },
  {
    ID: "100",
    Question: "You are halfway through your Agile project when there is a significant change to the project scope, after was found that the project would not be able to deliver the benefits it had promised. You check your project budget and there are contingency and management reserves available. What will you do next?",
    A: "Take the project scope change to the change control board for approval.",
    B: "Use the available contingency reserves to make the appropriate change to project scope.",
    C: "Review the change management plan for the change control process.",
    D: "Reprioritize the product backlog, including the new scope and begin work on the highest priority straight away.",
    Answer: "Reprioritize the product backlog, including the new scope and begin work on the highest priority straight away.",
    Reason: "Changes may occur as a result of a risk event, environment change, a deeper understanding of requirements, customer requests and more. Project teams should prepare a process for adapting plans throughout the project. In an Agile team, this may take the form of reprioritizing the backlog instead of a change control process with project baselines."
  }
]